

Sastelvio Serafim Manuel

• Address: Bairro Chuiba, Cabo Delgado Province, 3200, Pemba, Mozambique

Email address: sastelvio@gmail.com Email address: sastelvio@gmail.com

Phone number: (+258) 846052576 **Phone number:** (+258) 877242462

Website: http://www.sastelvio.com Skype: sstlv_seraph

in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/sastelviomanuel/

Nationality: Mozambican

ABOUT ME

I'm enthusiastic about computer science, especially it's logic. This is why I love to write code (software development). I have experience in Object-Oriented Programming using Java and C#; Relational Databases (SQL) with INGOs and freelancer assignments.

I like to work with data. This is why I'm continuously developing my skills in Data Science (e.g., data analysis with SQL, R, and Python), Information Management (e.g., collection tools such as Kobo Toolbox), Business Intelligence (e.g., Power BI and Tableau), and Machine Learning.

I'm always trying to find an equilibrium between what I do and what I like, but I also try to keep my discipline to do what needs to be done, so I keep an open mind to be flexible.

I like challenging environments because I know that there is where I can grow and develop myself.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[01/06/2022 - Current] ICT Senior Officer

Action Contre La Faim www.actioncontrelafaim.org

City: Pemba

Country: Mozambique

Main activities and responsibilities:

Covering all the country (Mozambique) mission, I:

- 1. Supervise the security of equipment and the use of mission IT resources:
 - Ensure that workstations adhere to IT standards.
 - Ensure that anti-virus software usage guidelines are followed, that updates are implemented on individual workstations, and that anti-virus protection is constantly monitored;
 - Oversee the data backup system (backup policy);
 - Install and maintain local networks at the mission according to standards (Router, WiFi AP, NAS Server, Internet Modem);
 - Maintaining computers, printers/scanners and performing daily/monthly checks to ensure maintenance tasks have been performed;
 - Capitalize data and procedures related to the use of computer resources and networks and communicate this information upstream to line management;
 - Ensure that all mission equipment is encrypted and recorded in the mission equipment list.
- 2. Improve the efficient use of IT resources:
 - Resolve day-to-day user problems;
 - Provide users with software support for file sharing, e-mail;
 - Suggest computer resources that can be implemented to improve the efficiency of users' work according to ACF standards;
 - Report on problems encountered and solutions implemented.
- 3. Participate in the management of telecommunications resources (radio, satellite and local telephones and modem, Internet)
 - Ensure that the mission's communication means are working properly and monitor them;
 - Perform regular tests on their use.
- 4. Promote user awareness and train users in the use of ICT resources:
 - Train users on equipment and applications;
 - Train users on the use of IT equipment and software;
 - Train users in the proper use of IT resources, NAS server, and respect IT security rules;
 - Training the users (especially the registration team) on the correct use of Telecom media (Radio, Satellite, Internet).

[01/04/2022 - 31/05/2022] Livelihood and Food Security Officer, focus on Information Management

NRC Mozambique www.nrc.no

Address: Mueda, Mozambique

City: Mueda

Country: Mozambique

Email address: sastelvio.manuel@nrc.no

Name of unit or department: Livelihood and Food Security Programme

Business or sector: Human health and social work activities

Main activities and responsibilities:

- · Conduct livelihoods assessments to determine the most viable income-generating activities.
- Responsible for coordination with all key stakeholders and registering project beneficiaries.
- Create and maintain databases regarding all activities of the program.
- Coordinate with stakeholders and partners in training beneficiaries on small scale business, sustainability, agricultural activities and income-generating activities.
- Coordinate the food security activities according to strategy, proposals, budgets and plans.
- Ensure adherence to NRC policies and donor requirements.
- Involve and inform communities and community leaders about the activities.
- Break down the annual operational plans into weekly, monthly and quarterly implementation plans.
- Coordinate with relevant partners working in the same implementation areas.
- Ensure that procurement, development and distribution of materials and equipment are timely and according to procedures.
- Supervise, train and develop a team of food assistants.
- Prepare periodic progress reports and other documents as required using written and visual tools such as Microsoft Power BI, Microsoft Office Excel and Word.
- Investigate and facilitate the introduction of new technology, methods and approaches in order to improve the quality of the activities

[21/09/2021 - 31/03/2022] Graphic Design and Micro Data Entry Clerk

UNDP - United Nations Development Programme http://www.mz.undp.org/

City: Pemba

Country: Mozambique

Main activities and responsibilities:

- \circ Concept and Develop Structured Databases, Non-Strutured Databases and GIS Databases.
- Work with Data Visualisation Tools (Microsoft Power BI).
- Maintains, and protects operations by keeping the micro data confidential.
- Transform text-based communications materials into Visual Graphic Design.
- Prepares source data for computer entry by compiling and sorting information, and establishing data entry priorities.
- Secures information by completing data base backups.

[10/2021 - Current] Help desk: Project SUCCEED (Consultant, Part Time)

Solidarmed Mozambique https://www.solidarmed.ch/en/mozambique

City: Chiure

Country: Mozambique

Main activities and responsibilities:

Provide technical support on:

- Maintain the system up and running
- Troubleshooting and bug resolve
- $\,^\circ$ Assist the users on how to use and any issue regarding the production environment.

[07/2020 - 09/2021] Lead Software Developer (Consultant)

Solidarmed Mozambique https://www.solidarmed.ch/en/mozambique

Address: Chiure, Mozambique

City: Chiure

Country: Mozambique

https://succeed-solidarmed.github.io/

Main activities and responsibilities:

Solidarmed is a non-profit organization committed to improving the health of people in Sub-Saharan Africa. We work with national partners to strengthen health systems and community capacities. Scientific evidence and policy dialogue are the basis and objective of our work. They started a project called SUCCEED that aims to track, prevent and aid women with / with cervical cancer. In this project, I was responsible for leading the development team of a computer system (software) to be used to collect, process and storage the data over the project, initially implemented in the Chiure district, Cabo Delgado Province, Mozambique. Among my functions I can highlight: the Software Engineering of the system where I collect the requirements to be able to describe the functioning of it through diagrams (initially based on UML and RUP); Development of the system that starts from the writing of the source code until the Alpha and Beta tests; Training of end users of the system, ranging from training and creation of user support tools; Maintenance that consists in ensuring that the system is in full operation during the execution of the project.

[01/02/2016 - 31/03/2022] Assistant Professor (Software Programming, Database Design)

Catholic University of Mozambique www.ucm.ac.mz

Address: Av 25 de Setembro, 336, Pemba, Mozambique

City: Pemba

Country: Mozambique
Business or sector: Education
Main activities and responsibilities:

- Plan and teach classes related to information technologies
- Participate in reviewing the academic curriculum whenever requested

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

[01/03/2020 - Current] Master in Geographic Information Systems and Monitoring of Natural Resources

Catholic University of Mozambique www.ucm.ac.mz

Address: 25th Setembro Avenue, 725, Pemba, Mozambique

$[\ 01/09/2018-30/08/2019\]\ \textbf{Master in Energy and Environmental Sciences (Incomplete)}$

University of Groningen https://www.rug.nl/

Address: Groningen, Netherlands

[01/02/2012 - 19/09/2015] **Bachelor in Information Technology**

Catholic University of Mozambique www.ucm.ac.mz

Address: 25th Setembro Avenue, 725, Pemba, Mozambique

Main subject / occupational skills covered:

- Object Oriented Programming
- Java Programming
- Relational Database Design and Implementation
- Computer Network Configuration
- Server Configuration
- Web Programming (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
- Enterprise Software Developer
- Software

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Portuguese

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

[10/10/2022 - 14/10/2022] **ICT Workshop 2022** Paris, France

Organized by Action Contre La Faim, was discussed:

- 1. Information Systems
- 2. Energy Management at ICT perspective
- 3. Project Collaboraion
- 4. Environment at ICT perspective
- 5. Equipment Life Cycle
- 6. Telecom
- 7. Data Management
- 8. Security
- 9. Azure AD
- 10. MDM (Mobile Device Management)
- 11. Infrastructure

PROJECTS

[01/07/2020 - Current] Principal Developer for the SUCCEED Project

- 1. Collaboration in gathering requirements for the system;
- 2. Collaboration in the design of the system;
- 3. Coordination of the system implementation team;
- 4. Coordination of the deployment and testing team;
- 5. Collaboration in the maintenance of the system;

https://succeed-solidarmed.github.io/

[01/06/2020 - Current] Member of the Technical Team of the Pemba City Navigator Project

- 1. Create a platform that allows improved accessibility to basic resources for the prevention of COVID-19 in the city of Pemba;
- 2. Project with the Municipal Council of the City of Pemba as the main partner;

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Telecommunication Systems Digital Analog Communications | ICT Infrastructure Management | Software Development and Software Engineering | Database Design and Implementation | Microsoft Power Platform (Power BI, Power Apps, Power Automate) | ArcGIS